How Many Could Be Saved?
Last Days in Vietnam is a war, documentary film directed by Rory Kennedy.
During the chaotic final weeks of the Vietnam War, the North Vietnamese Army closes in on
Saigon as the panicked South Vietnamese people desperately attempt to escape.
On the ground, American soldiers and diplomats confront a moral quandary:
whether to obey White House orders to evacuate only U.S.
Last Days in Vietnam is a 2014 American documentary film
written, produced and directed by Rory Kennedy.
The film had its world premiere at 2014 Sundance
Film Festival on January 17, 2014.
After its premiere at Sundance Film Festival, American Experience Films acquired the
distribution rights of the film, in association with PBS Distribution for DVD releases.
The film had a theatrical release in New York City on September 5, 2014, before
expanding nationwide in the United States during September and early October.
The film was nominated for the Academy Award for Best
Documentary Feature at the 87th Academy Awards.
It also garnered a nomination for Best Documentary
Screenplay from the Writers Guild of America.
It premiered on PBS television on April 28, 2015.
The film explores themes of vietnam war, vietnam, woman
director, vietnamese refugees, fall of saigon.